good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to icic Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q3 and nine
months fy23 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargram Das Gupta mdn CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mantri executive director and
Mr alok Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements or
comments are made in today's call they
that may look like forward-looking
statements are based on information
presently available to the management
and do not constitute an indication of
any future performance as future
involves risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to differ materially
from the current views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star then zero
on your Touchstone phone
I know in the conference over to Mr
Margaret vasgupta mdn CEO ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to yourself
as always I will give you a brief
overview of the industry Trends and
developments that we've witnessed in the
past few months post this RCA for Mr
gopal balachandran will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter and nine months ended
December 31 2022.
during the quarter the Indian economy
was largely driven by domestic
consumption with activity across the
industry and services sectors in
expansion mode
credit growth has been showing
double-digit growth since April 2020
supported by both retail and wholesale
Lending however the synchronized
tightening of policy raised by global
central banks has been slowing down
Global demand and international trade
Global slowdown has been putting
pressure on the current account and can
adversely impact domestic growth going
for going forward
for the quarter as for data published by
CM the new vehicle sales continue to
deliver strong growth year on year for
Private Car segments with continued
momentum in the underlying Insurance
demand
the commercial vehicle segment growth
was supported by robust growth in
individual Industries such as
infrastructure and e-commerce while the
two wheeler segment grew on a smaller
base however in volume terms the segment
continues to remain below pre-pandemic
levels
health insurance continue to drive the
overall industry growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
line with the current market environment
we remain optimistic that the insurance
industry will continue to grow given the
low penetration favorable regulatory
changes and positive consumer sentiment
speaking of the performance the GI
industry delivered a gdpi growth of 16.2
percent for nine months f523
excluding crop the growth of 17.5 for
the same period at the same time the
underwriting performance remained poor
with a combined ratio of the industry at
116.6 percent
as on half year 2023 for motor business
combined ratio for the industry was
123.5 percent for half year 2023 as
compared to 110.4 for half year 2022 as
for public disclosures
foreign
in The Current financial year has
introduced various reforms seeking to
expand the market and increase the
penetration of insurance products
towards its mission of insurance for for
all by 2047. during the quarter there
and the authority mandated kyc
requirements with effect from January
March 2023 notified the increase in
number of tires from three to nine in
case of Corporations for each category
of insurance
notified regulatory sandbox regulations
eliminated in the time limit to facility
innovation in products for Solutions and
to increase the experimental period up
to 36 months
considered working committee to put in
place effective regulatory framework
post the notification of existing tariff
wordings Under Fire engineering and
motor OD
or exposure drafts has been issued for
long-term motor insurance products
covering motorod and motor TV and
long-term fire Insurance products
the authorities also issued registration
of insurance company regulations
simplifying persons of registration for
insurance companies and to promote ease
of building
we believe that these changes will be
disruptive in the short term but we'll
have a positive effect on the insurance
penetration over the long term
moving to business impact for us during
the quarter the company grew by 16.9
percent as compared to the industry
growth of 18.1 percent excluding crop
the company grew by 17.1 percent
coming to the growth for key segments
during the quarter in motor OD because
then what are the growth remain Mutual
at 4.7 percent the competitive intensity
continued on the motor would be side
especially on the private car segment we
continue to focus on profitable sub
segments using historical granular data
and rebalance our portfolio resulting in
CV mix at 22.2 percent for nine months
of FY 23.
similarly to the previous year Health
segment continued to be the fastest
growing segment for the industry during
the quarter we grew at 47.9 which was
significantly higher than the industry
growth of 24.9 percent
as a result of our continued investment
in health and Retail Health distribution
we have outgrown the industry in
Standalone players with the growth of
24.2 percent this was given by business
source through retail health agency
vertical which grew at which grew at
40.1 percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs I'll take care of as a
past 3.7 million user downloads in date
the incremental download for the quarter
was
0.9 million I'll take care I have
contributed 33 47.9 million to the gdpi
of Q3 fi 23. our time questions and key
relationship groups grew at 39.3 this
quarter within this its Bank
distribution grew by 30.9 and non icsm
distribution grew by 44.2 percent
post pandemic the recovery and credit
growth along with increase in wallet
share and distribution Partners acquired
through the de Merchant has been the
keyboard drivers
our business source through our digital
one team do a Google 20 20.
our digital Focus has enabled us to
increase our digital revenues to 2.62
billion rupees which a consequent
accounts for 4.8 percent of our overall
GDP gbpa for this quarter this excludes
revenues from I'll take care I have
mentioned earlier
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robust growth
driven by growth of 25.2 percent in the
SME segment
we remain on track and are focused on
growth diversity Innovation digital and
advancements new products strengthening
distribution engine rationalizing costs
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers so the
result be concluded quarter
thanks Marcus and uh good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview on the financial
performance of the company for quarter
three and nine months of fy23 we have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website you can access it as we walk you
through the performance numbers
the GDP of the company was rupees 160.48
billion in nine months fy23 as against
rupees 1.133.11 billion in nine months
at 522 a growth of 20.6 percent which
was higher than the industry growth of
16.2 percent
excluding crop GDP growth of the company
was at 19.9 which was higher than the
industry growth of 17.5 percent in nine
months and 523
gdpa was at 54.93 billion rupees in
quarter three fi23 as against rupees
46.99 billion in quarter three f522 the
growth of 16.9 percent as against
industry growth of 18.1 percent
excluding crop GDP growth of the company
was at 17.1 percent which was higher
than the industry growth of 16.6 percent
in quarter three up by 23. our gdpi
growth was primarily driven by growth in
the preferred segments the overall GDP
of our Property and Casualty segment
grew by 17.8 percent at rupees 46.35
billion in nine months f523 as against
rupees 39.34 billion and 9.22. on the
retail side of the business GDP of the
motor segment was at rupees 64 billion
in 9 months after 23 asked against 58.15
billion in 9 months of 522 registering a
growth of 10.1 percent
our agents including point of sale or
POS count was at one lakh six thousand
one one nine as on December 31 2022 up
from
one lakh 636 as on September 30 2052 the
advanced premium was rupees 32.79
billion as at December 31 22 as against
rupees 34.34 billion as at September 30
22.
resultantly combined ratio was
104.6 percent in nine nine months at 523
as against 111 percent in nine months at
combined ratio was 104.4 percent in
quarter three apply 23 asking a 104.5
in quarter three fy22 our investment
assets Rose to 414.51 billion as at
December 3122 up from 400.96 billion as
at September 30 2022. our investment
leverage net of borrowings was 4.16
times as at December 31 2022 as against
4.08 times as at September 30 2022
investment income was at rupees 21.6
billion in nine months f523 as against
rupees 22.95 billion in nine months f522
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to rupees 7.66 billion in
quarter three fi23 as against rupee 6.9
billion in quarter three fi 22. our
capital gains net of impairment on
Equity investment assets stood at rupees
2.94 billion in 9 months at 523 as
compared to rupees 6.01 billion in 9
months at 522. capital gains in quarter
three f523 was at rupees 1.52 billion as
compared to rupees 1.31 billion in
quarter three fy22
our profit before tax grew by 21 at 15.4
billion rupees in nine months f523
that's against 12.73 billion rupees in
nine months of the previous year
whereas profit before tax grew by 10.5
percent at rupees 4.65 billion in
quarter three or five twenty three as
against rupees 4.21 billion in quarter
three f522 consequently profit after tax
grew by 34.8 percent at rupees 12.92
billion in nine months f523 as against
rupees 9.59 billion nine months of 522
whereas profit after tax grew by 11 at
rupees 3.53 billion in quarter three
f523 from rupees 3.18 billion in quarter
three fi 22. that includes reversal of
tax division of rupees 1.28 billion in
quarter to f523 excluding this growth
impact was 21.4 percent for 9 month f523
return on average Equity was 18.1
percent in nine months f523 as against
fifteen point one percent in nine months
up by 22. the return on average equity
for quarter three fi 23 was a 14.3
percent as against 14.6 percent in
quarter three fy22 solvency ratio was at
2.45 times as a December 31 2022 as
against 2.47 times as at September 30 22
continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times as I
conclude I would like to reiterate we
continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policyholders at all times
I would like to thank you for attending
this earnings call and we would be happy
to take any questions at least you may
have thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one only that stone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
reminder to the participants anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one
the first question is from the lineup
Mukherjee from bnk Securities please go
ahead
good evening sir thank you for the
opportunity and congrats for the number
your retail Health segment number seems
to be panning out very nicely so just
wanted to understand on that segment in
a little bit more detail you have
shared that they you will see a segment
in retail Health has grown by 40 percent
the audio is not clear from your line
please use the handset mode
yeah just give me a moment
yes
yeah is this better
yes it's better yes okay okay so so uh
on the retail health agency uh side if
you could give some color on uh what
would be share in the mix and uh how do
you anticipate this to be growing uh
going ahead that would be very helpful
because that growth of 40 percent must
have come on a slightly smaller base so
will that growth rate sustain or how
will it plan out that is the first
question that I have second is on the
motor TP loss ratio so this quarter the
number is very very strong so how should
we think about that particularly that
you know this quarter I am seeing that
there has been some amount of themes in
the gdpa mix between two wheeler and CV
so is that also a quarterly kind of a
thing which should reverse because I
thought that you wanted to keep CV at
around 24 25
so broadly these are my questions
so maybe the specific to the people are
so she will ask Bhopal to answer but to
answer your first question on uh
on the retail Health business as we've
been saying when you uh invest in a in
the scale that we are doing uh you know
relative to our current size it takes
time for people to come in stabilize uh
you know higher agents for the agents to
become active and then productive it
takes some time so we've been saying it
will start building up uh maybe you know
three to six months from the time that
we started talking about it so this
quarter is the first quarter where we
are beginning to see you know real
impact of the investment that we are
making
but this is still uh you know early days
we are very confident that this growth
number for the retail health agency
channel will sustain going ahead overall
health growth will be given by multiple
other factors you will have to look at
what happens when the bank issue and
share side because if you look at our
group health number that's also growing
quite fast compared to the industry
that's driven by two reasons one the
bank accounts channels that we've talked
about you know both in terms of what
came through through the acquisition as
also in terms of our existing Partners
they are going uh really well uh ICC
bank has been going well uh in this
quarter so those other channels are
largely driven by a slight share of
quality increase while largely and but
however large is driven by credit growth
so if that will be the dynamic for that
segment of the group health business and
Commercial corporate grouping which is a
you know b2b2e as in for employees
GMC or GHA whatever you call it that
segment is largely driven by pricing so
right now we are increasing pricing we
are still winning accounts because I
think the market is finally stabilizing
in terms of sizing so that growth will
uh come through as long as the pricing
is to our satisfaction so that's to give
you an overall perspective on help but
specific if your question is on retail
health agency growth can we sustained 40
we believe we can
okay okay so any any color on the mix
how much would be retail health agency
now in your overall retail health
number would be things
so I think relatively I think it's kind
of doing well uh if you look at our
overall
retail Health Indemnity that number
would afford that water would have kind
of grown by almost about 25-26 percent
uh within that I think the agency
vertical has kind of grown at about 40
percent
so hence I think as Vargo mentioned one
of the other things that we have been
talking to the market is to try and
sustain whether on
retail Health Indemnity can be sustained
a growth numbers which is faster than
not just the industry but even the
Standalone Health companies but at least
for the last four months in September
onwards I think we have been able to
kind of demonstrate that I think the key
will be to sustain it as we kind of look
forward but really we are kind of
optimistic and we are continuing to make
those investments in uh
uh in the retail Health distribution
franchise
uh to your second point on the TP loss
ratios and let's say relative and
corresponding to that let's say the CV
mix
insofar as a thought process is
concerned at least on the selection of
business mix within motor there is no
change in thought process which is to
say that while the market continues to
remain competitive at least on certain
segments of private car for sure and
therefore we continue to take a
calibrated position wherever we see
opportunities whether it's on two
wheeler or CV I think obviously we have
been writing those profitable segments
as what we indicated as a part of our
opening remarks in the process is what
we had indicated that possibly our mix
of commercial vehicles could stay a
range bound within let's say around that
24 25 threshold in that quarter that
number going down to let's say 22
percent mix I think obviously is a
function of what kind of uh business mix
that one is able to Source in a
particular quarter and given the fact
that Q3 generally is a seasonal quarter
when it comes to let's say writing of
risks between Private Car two wheelers
and commercial vehicles
thought process is concerned I think so
far as the year end mix is concerned we
should get to see the CV around that
range of uh 23 24 kind of levels is what
one would say so this is the pH with
water where there are not of festive
demand for private current two wheeler
so those numbers get elevated in this
quarter that's the reason why the mix is
relatively smaller for CV nothing else
yeah and to your other point on the TP
loss ratio
again that's what we keep saying uh I
mean you have to obviously look at uh
loss ratios again not between quarters
obviously you have to look at it
moreover longer uh longer periods uh
ideally at an ear today year end basis
is the best way to kind of look at the
TP loss issues because in some quarters
you will obviously see the effect of
some of the uh some of the let's say
positions that we'd have taken from a
reserving perspective that we would
start to see it getting played out in so
far as actual launch development
experiences are concerned so and since
in that particular quarter you may
possibly see some kind of a release of
reserves that would have kind of been
given effect to and corresponding to
that is what you get to see the
outcoming so far as the TP loss ratio
numbers are concerned but otherwise in
so far as the reserving philosophy is
concerned I don't think we have there is
any change in the reserving philosophy
it pretty much Remains the Same
but more the TP loss ratios over not
just on a quarter on quarter basis but
look at it more over longer periods of
development
she also got it uh very helpful can I
squeeze in one quick question on the
expensive ratio side if you if you could
throw some light on how to think about
it in terms of maybe capex and Opex and
you know think about it going ahead
except for the next three four quarters
how it will pan out because it continues
to remain elevated close to around 30
percent
what essentially happens is uh
particularly when you are continuing
with your investments in various areas
of opportunities that we have spoken
about in terms of long-term growth
potential
whether it is with respect to
the opportunity that we see on the
digital side or even for the matter of
fact the continued investment that we
are making on building the retail Health
distribution franchise where it's not
just a one-off addition to Manpower that
we did last year that's a continuing one
even as we speak in the current period
as well now all of this is something as
what we have been explaining in our
earlier calls will entail an uprighting
of expenses
the benefit of revenues is obviously
something that will get paid out over a
period of time now as I mentioned in
response to the earlier one clearly we
are seeing early signs of some of those
Investments getting played out in terms
of our growth percentages reflecting
those Investments and hence
given the fact that this is a continuing
one we will obviously get to see the
expense ratio stay at the current levels
at where we are kind of largely
operating at having said that we will
obviously Monitor and come back to the
market and give an update in terms of
how those Investments are playing out in
each of each of the areas
so that's something that will be a
continuing one uh obviously Revenue will
catch up your other point on let's say
some of the Investments between capex
and Optics I think that's something that
we it's again an ongoing one uh as we
have been talking through we do
undertake various transformational
projects which will keep the
organization future ready uh in terms of
our ability to deliver products and
services to the market and hence that
extent you will obviously see continuing
Investments whether it is on capex or
whether it is for that matter of fact
any operating expenses the only aspect
that I will add is from Q4 onwards in
line with what we have been again
talking about we have been able to
successfully complete the technology
migration
which we have kind of indicated that we
will complete it by quarter three of
this year that's pretty much kind of
done and hence to that extent the
benefit of whatever amount of synergies
that we were expected to realize out of
those technology expense is something
that we will start to see from Q4
onwards
just one more comment to add what took
over what gopal said so as we shared
with you last year we moved our entire
technology stack to the cloud right so
all our applications are Cloud so that's
the call that we've taken not from a
capex versus office perspective because
all of that you know part of the
capacity in future will be convert into
Opex so that's the call that we've taken
in the interest of business from a
longer term perspective it gives us more
uh agility more you know elasticity so
you know more scalability so all of that
factors go in our decision from a longer
term perspective rather than looking at
whether we want to keep that expense
on-prem and kind of advertise cost over
period and you know look at capex versus
Optics to manage your financials
thank you
May request that you return to the
question key for follow-up questions
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants in the
conference please limit your questions
to two per participant should you have a
follow-up question we would request you
to rejoin the question came the next
question is from the line of Avinash
from MK Global Financial Services please
go ahead
yeah hi or good evening a couple of
questions and both looking at nine must
data just to sort of a clear out the
noise of water to water or firstly I
mean now the combined ratio at around
say 100 405 that is where you have
indicated now because of this uh you
know uh investment side volatility and
if I were to remove the tax refund or
this hundred four hundred five percent
combined issue is leading to a more of a
sixteen percent kind of Roe now is that
where I mean you are comfortable because
I mean uh if the investment yields
continue to be at this level probably
this combined ratio means that uh the uh
Ro is at 16 or percent level so are you
comfortable with uh this thing I mean
you can argue that I mean where industry
is of sector is you are much better and
that I admit but I mean of course you
don't have the advantage of not being
listed you are listed companies of
course you are monitored on all the
return parameters so that's question on
sort of for your you know balancing your
combined is your growth and
profitability that number one and number
two again I if I look at motor as a
combined portfolio uh you know uh what I
see uh there is like uh on a year on
your basis your loss if you are more or
less fine I mean that's 100 basis point
movement uh but if I just go and uh sort
of uh delve down into underwriting
results it it suggests that I mean uh
overall or there's a kind of a material
increase on the optic side in motor so
if you can just help us understand what
is or is the Opex or that is driving uh
perhaps that uh you know a higher
underwriting losses on a nine months
basis on an overall motor portfolio
motivation thank you so let's let me
take the first one and then ask gopal to
give you a breakdown of uh you know
where that is coming from in terms of
motor underwriting uh on the first as
we've articulated the
since the time when that we uh
transaction we had said that we there
were certain Synergy benefits that we
were we had assumed but in reality we
are seeing higher Synergy benefits we
felt that it was appropriate from a
longer term perspective to invest that
for uh for growth and that is what we
did I mean it was really a capital
allocation call of
looking at the longer term versus some
short-term efficiency
we also said that in the first couple of
years maybe the combination will be
elevated while Endeavor will always be
to reduce it and bring it closer to
maybe 102 in a couple of years
So to that extent our uh our view or our
our Outlook hasn't changed uh
if that happens obviously our Ro is as
we've indicated in the past will be in
the high teens now you can calculate the
array for yourself it will probably be
higher than 16 if it if we achieve the
objective that we set for ourselves it
is also a fact that you know during this
period we probably did not anticipate
the uh pricing resolution on the motor
OD side to the extent that we've
experienced in the last six months uh
that has had uh you know some impact on
us this year but what we are seeing is
that uh finally we are seeing some
calibration some moderation we have seen
some early signs of improvement and if
that happens uh you know that will help
us in achieving the objective that we've
talked about so hopefully you know just
to explain your answer your question uh
it is not about being comfortable where
we are this is really a short-term
journey to achieve something which is
more value trading for the longer term
objective in the longer term is
continues to be improving combined and
improving our ways
and your second point on the motor uh
underwriting experience Avinash uh uh I
think it's a function of two things one
is uh obviously you will have to look at
it in the context of what kind of growth
are we exhibiting uh so relative to
let's say the market yes you would have
seen clearly on motor in the aggregate
we have kind of underperformed which is
a conscious call that we're kind of
taking
in order to kind of stay focused on uh
just selecting portfolios which is from
a profitability perspective
uh and to that extent obviously there is
a denominator effect that tends to play
out when it comes to the expensive
issues
and two uh given the fact that at the
end of the day there is obviously a set
of expenses that you can identify with a
particular segment but equally there are
large expenses which are which are of
let's say of a fixed nature which
typically gets allocated between various
uh product lines and therefore to that
extent that will also be a function of
let's say what outcome that you see and
so far as the overall expense ratios for
a particular segment is concerned which
is why uh instead of maybe specifically
looking at individual lines of
businesses uh from an uh expense ratio
standpoint it is rather better to look
at the overall expense ratios for the
company as a whole which if you look at
it at least on a whether you look at it
on a nine month to nine month basis uh I
mean uh orbits let's say even for the
matter of fact when you look at those
numbers on a quarter on quarter basis
the the expense ratios have kind of
largely stayed around the threshold of
around 29.5 to around let's say 30
thereabout uh so hence as growth gets
revived particularly in the context of
motor and the fact that as we have kind
of indicated the market at this point of
time is obviously competitive which is
why as a part of the opening remarks we
also specifically put out
for motor the industry combined ratios
continue to stay elevated at almost
about 124 percent
and hence once we start to see as what
Bardo also mentioned some bit of easing
is what we have seen but once we start
seeing the cycle completely turning back
we will be obviously able to get the
growth back and therefore to that extent
you will also see maybe the expense
ratios getting allocated to that segment
reflecting better numbers
thank you Mr Avinash may we request that
to return to the question give for
follow-up questions
the next question is from The Lion of
Shreya Shivani from clsa please
yeah thank you I have three questions my
first question is on the yields of
investment uh sorry the uh realize the
investment yield so that came in at
about 1.88 for this quarter and uh if we
sort of plot your yields versus The
Five-Year GSA killed
performance uh this your yields have
sort of ranged between 1.7 to 2 on
quarterly basis since even during FY
2021 when the gcules were at its lowest
in the recent past right so I'm trying
to understand where are we missing on
the yields bit if you can help me
understand that because my main question
is that we would be we were expecting
this to be uh higher than what it has
turned out to be first is on that second
is on the uh crop book so for the nine
month period the loss ratio is sort of
inched up to 90 now last time you had
mentioned that you've written a big
chunk of uh this business with
Maharashtra government which which has
some Gap loss program at 80 80 110 or
something like that so uh how is the
performance of that book and whether
this inching up of the loss ratio is
from the bharti aksa book so just trying
to understand where the higher loss
ratio is coming from and on third is on
retail Health uh the last you had
mentioned that you guys have hired a
thousand uh retail Health sales managers
and each one of them will go out and
onboard more agents Etc so if you can
give us an update on whether all those
thousand onboarding is finished are we
hiring more sales manager and how is
that process going
thank you so let me uh you know respond
in the same sequence so if you look at
the realized yield it's a it's an
annualized number so for the on an
annualized basis that reflects roughly
about 7.52 which given the current
interest regime is uh you would think is
pretty good in terms of uh you know
realizing yield on the portfolio uh
on the second one uh in terms of the
crop so uh our entire Chromebook is a
book so there is a book in our book
everything that we have Isa book there
is no change in terms of what we are
seeing with the with the book
performance in Q2 which is last quarter
based on actual realization of the
uh experience we had some releases
we of course that you know we do is that
till we get the complete results we tend
to reserve conservatively and then once
we actually get the final data then we
release if at all there is a scope for
release we release that so this quarter
we've reserved as a as a practice in a
conservative manner our belief is on the
underlying voice is what we get to see
the kharif uh you know the Ravi losses
are well within our comfort level and
Curry's Crop Production also sorry
kharif has been well within our comfort
level rabi crop production also we think
should be good given the uh wonderful
rainfall that we've had so crop looks
comfortable for us at this point in time
but again you know these are these
answers and businesses we will see what
happens in Ravi but there are big
proportion of our business is also very
small so we don't think it will have a
material impact even if it goes against
our anticipated uh you know losses uh on
the uh last one
yeah so on the retail Health Shreya just
to answer yes we have kind of pretty
much onboarded all the Thousand retail
health agency managers that were kind of
spoken of to be hired that's pretty much
kind of done and as I said this is the
continuing one it's not that it's one of
Investments that we wanted to do in that
we spoke of it since Quarter Two of last
year so that's a continuing one and
that's and as I had indicated obviously
early signs of uh early signs have been
getting played out is what I spoke about
since September onwards we are getting
to see month on month Traction in US
clearly exhibiting also for months
relative to even the Standalone Health
companies I think the key will be for us
to kind of sustain this momentum as we
kind of build up this distribution for
the end of the day as we have kind of
also indicated in the past the market
share on retail health for us is still
at sub three percent it's about 2.9 to
three percent in that range so there is
clearly an opportunity for us to kind of
stay invested and possibly try and
increase market share
sure just one clarification so the
Maharashtra crop book was also a part of
the bharti bharti book or uh I thought
that was a new new uh uh contract that
you guys have entered into
so yeah in that sense yes but this is
basically bharti AXA had a Maharashtra
business we've kind of renewed it this
year based on the 1810 model you're
right
please go ahead
thank you for giving me an opportunity
so firstly I wanted to understand on
agency in retail Health how many agents
would have been added so for instance if
we have 1000 new sales force uh how many
agents would be active in health so I
think in the past we had about 6 000
agents selling health so what would that
number be right now
I'll just give you a number we'll come
back to you with the number sure and so
the second question I had was uh so
these benefit policies I assume other
than the icfa bank the other
Partnerships that we have we are doing
uh attachment products with them and
these policies generally tend to be
quite profitable so is that this
scenario and should we expect that uh
combined ratio in this segment will be
good with all these distribution
Partnerships that we are working on
so absolutely it is I think uh if you
recollect uh while the mix currently on
health for us is cured more in terms of
Indemnity as compared to benefit but if
you look at historically the mix was
actually the opposite where we had a
relatively large proportion of Health
premiums contributed more by the benefit
product and relatively at that point of
time we were building up the indemnity
franchise for the last couple of years
for the benefit segment because of
Market constraints in terms of credit
disposals being significantly lower and
also what we have explained in terms of
the decision that one of our Bank
distribution partner had taken now all
of that is behind us which is why now as
we speak the credit dispersals is back
and this segment is obviously a
profitable one and that's it and yes you
are right it's a it's something that
will kind of contribute to our
underwriting outcomes and in general the
product segment is positive
it's just it's just one last thing said
an investment income on a qoq basis is
lower but I think on capital gains it's
not materially different can you just
guide on that
so there is no specific consideration
behind that hitesh because uh I think uh
between quarters uh in so far as capital
gain numbers are concerned that could
also kind of vary between periods to
periods but otherwise it is pure as we
have always indicated in general when
you look at the breakup of our overall
investment income uh roughly about three
fourth of that investment income tends
to be through invest through accruals
and roughly about one-fourth happens to
capital gains now it's quite possible
that in some quarter you have a capital
gain number which is precisely higher in
mix but otherwise between quarters there
is no specific change in the underlying
investment thought process in general I
think obviously we are changing this
opportunity of higher interest rates
which are which obviously kind of occurs
well in so far as higher accruals are
concerned and hence to that extent is
what you get to see the income between
quarter to quarter more as an outcome as
compared to anything that is
specifically contributing to it
the next question is from the line of
prayers Jain from motilal as well please
go ahead
yeah hi just a couple of questions from
my side uh gopal if you could mention uh
how do we think about the unexpired risk
reserve for The Courier of fa 23 now
that you have gone into nine months and
I I understand that it depends on what
kind of growth we see in the in the
remainder in in fourth quarter but
assuming a ballpark growth around what
we've seen around 15 percent do we see
uh uh you know the NAT uh growth to be
better going ahead that is one secondly
uh so from a reserve sorry sorry in the
motor segment uh uh I would like your
views as to when do we really see growth
coming strongly in the end for you guys
you know uh what would be the point or
what are the factors that can really
drive this growth uh back to a high you
know like in line with industry are even
better than the industry and in the past
you've been alluding to the fact that
past few quarters that the motor OD
pricing has become more or less you know
is getting some cognizance and it's
getting better but we don't see that in
the numbers yet so uh any further
thoughts there that would be helpful
yeah
the first one
when it comes to unexpired exclusive
it's purely a function of
what kind of business mix that you write
and the earnings is purely a function of
the uh contract term for which let's say
the policies are issued and hence to
that extent like for example if a large
part of our colleagues are predominantly
of a one year duration and as to that
actually the earnings will typically
kind of get uh earned over the contract
period uh so so hence to that extent uh
given the fact that let's say for
example this particular year we have
seen let's say the growth being
relatively better than what we had seen
let's say in the past two periods which
is why you get to see in whichever
period you are writing the higher
Quantum of business
to that extent for the period at which
you're ending up reporting numbers you
end up carrying a higher amount of
unexpected result which will obviously
get released in the future periods
outcome will be to look at more because
corresponding to that you would also
have let's say the loss experience
getting uh played out as well yeah so
rather it is better to look at more
either the loss ratio numbers for the
company as a whole or more importantly I
think combined issues will be far more a
better reflection rather than just
looking at the NEP on a standalone basis
because it has got multiple factors as
you rightly mentioned in terms of mix of
business at what point of time are you
kind of writing those risks and so on
and so forth so hence better better way
to kind of look at is more let's say the
loss ratios and the combined ratios so
that's in response to the first one uh
to your second point on when do we see
let's say US changing stance I think
obviously we have this is not the first
time that we have been kind of taking a
calibrated call with with respect to
going a little slow in writing certain
segments of business now that's the
reason why just to kind of repeat what
we had put out as a part of the
introductory
opening remarks is what you get to see
as an outcome for the overall Market
with respect to the motor combined
ratios
okay really you see this is public
information so which is why I mean the
industry as a whole is operating at a
combined of 124 percent right obviously
does not make viable sense for us to
kind of significantly go after that
segment which is going to exhibit a very
adverse underwriting outcome that's the
reason why we have been taking
calibrated calls in the segments where
we think the competitive intensity is
far more elevated but our sales is given
that now we are seeing maybe continued
quarters of combined ratio staying
eliminated for the market we don't think
this can something that can continue to
sustain for maybe a further longer
period of time already we are seeing
which is what Varga also mentioned
um uh we are clearly seeing signs of
some of the players in the market
starting to become far more rational
when it comes to underwriting this
particular segment so our services we
will obviously watch out for the
development over the next couple of
quarters and then but at least in so far
as our investments is concerned I think
we are pretty much staying on force in
the sense that we are kind of expanding
investments in expanding distribution
even on the motor side whether it comes
to working with oems in terms of the
number of dealers whom we have access to
or for the matter of fact even with the
number of agents that we are working
with which is what you would have seen
for the company as a whole again the
aggregate number of agency count has
kind of gone up so we are continuing to
make those investments in writing those
businesses as and when we see the
opportunity turn up we are trying a
better place to write this particular
segment of business
thank you Mr Jane May request not to
return to the question queue for
follow-up questions
the next question is from the line of
sanket Goda from spark Capital please go
ahead
uh thank you for the opportunity uh can
you give me the lottery for breakdown
for retail Health to benefit based
health and Group Health and Pa is
possible but just just to understand how
it is panning out given given the last
part of the business will be new in
nature this this wanted to understand
whether it is it is substantially below
60 or 65 especially in case somebody to
indemnity
there's a kid uh I think I'm just giving
you right now quarter three numbers
uh quarter three loss ratios for the
corporate health book which is a ghi
portfolio that number is 98.9 and
insofar as the retail Indemnity book is
concerned that number is set up instead
about 68 percent
okay
I'm just really still asking because we
got 68 uh is is which means it might be
a 2 or 30 percent Roe products which
means you are chasing a product which
will drag down the entire Roi of the
company services I just wanted to
understand this 68 is like a sustainable
number what you look to the kind of
growth you are delivering or or it could
come down in your view
one is the mix of new versus old so our
new mix is increasing as we are you know
the of the fresh business is increasing
but that uh that any P of that book
hasn't thrown in as much so as that
happens uh the last ratio uh is expected
to come down a bit second is we are also
looking at repricing the reinsurance
sorry the uh the the renewal book which
is something that we will do
in this quarter itself so overall we
expect the last ratio to further thumb
down going ahead got it and in in health
I mean it has been a phenomenal year for
us this year at least for nine months so
so out of the entire Health if I look
the pa uh benefit-based health and Group
Health are are driven by some some kind
of a factors which are not repeatable in
nature like like credit growth being
very strong and and Group Health Rising
being better so so I mean I just wanted
to check whether the group health
pricing you have already seen a
correction and and if on a higher base
the credit growth slows down then the
highly profitable products like benefit
based and PM might contribute lower in
the next year uh so so so uh this just
wanted to know retail Indemnity Ico
highlighted might might do well because
of the English ones you have made but
but the kind of growth what you have
reported Health NPA 40 percent plus uh
in in in overall for nine months what
likely number you expect it to moderate
in in 24.
we used to have roughly 75 of our
business in the health coming from the
vacation you know the retail benefit
structure so uh this year it looks like
suddenly it's increased because of the
low base of the last two years uh going
ahead do we expect credit go to uh I
mean particularly for let's say uh
retail product you know retail price go
to come down significantly
uh you know that's a problem if it comes
down 1654 many some other uh you know
macroeconomic reasons of course it will
come down in terms of but we believe
that you know we are one gaining market
share and most of the uh Bank Insurance
Partners that we are working with we are
looking at opening up other streams of
businesses from each one of these
Partners which we believe there's an
opportunity so we really were reasonably
confident of going the um beneficials
business may not be the same rate given
that we have a very high growth this
year on that base maybe it will not be
the same rate of growth but we remain
confident of going that that channel the
second question that you had in terms of
Group Health pricing look at the end of
the day of course it is driven by
pricing someone could come in and you
know get very aggressive that is a
possibility but if you go back to the
reason why the Google pricing was the
level where it was it was largely a few
large uh you know uh companies who were
doing it in an aggressive uh level most
of them today has some solvency channels
challenges and we really don't
anticipate them coming back and doing
the same thing uh you know right now
there is still a capital concern there
so we believe that the market for Group
Health
structurally is getting better
and we believe that this goes through
sustain for some more time and in terms
of price increase we took a price
increase as we discussed last year we
had talked about postcode we are taking
15 to 20 price increase on that base we
are able to get further price increases
not at the same Pace but we are still
able to get small price increases and
and hold on to the business the other
thing that is happening in health is
that in Q2 we had talked about the fact
that the claims the frequency had got
elevated we are seeing that uh
rationalize and and kind of come down to
uh normal levels so from all of those
perspective we remain recently
considered over the health business as
of now
thank you Mr Buddha May request that to
return to the question thank you for
follow-up questions ladies and Gentlemen
please limit your questions to one per
participant should you have a follow-up
question we would request you to rejoin
the question queue
the next question is from the line of
nidesh from investec please go ahead
thanks for the opportunities in your
opening comments you mentioned that
there has been multiple regulatory drops
and uh proposed changes and that could
have a disruptive uh impact on the
company on the on the sector in the
short term so can you elaborate what
sort of disruption you are expecting
because of those changes
okay any any uh you know when there are
changes there will be uh some uh you
know consequent chill uh impact on the
ground right and what we are seeing is a
plethora of changes happening at the
same time so it's just that uh you know
let's look at couple of things that
could create the amount of disruption
one is uh you know fresh licensing it
may not come in by next year but if that
comes in there's a lot more Capital
coming into the sector that could create
some uh competitive question uh you know
that's a possibility I'm not saying it
will happen but these are things that
you you know you need to be conscious of
and aware of secondly for example
commercial line there is a talk of
complete detailification if that happens
there could be a round of
computerization uh you know we don't
believe that it will have dramatic
changes because uh if you look at the
overall uh combined ratio of the sector
and some of the players who are very
aggressive last time when this happened
they may not have the capability or the
capital to continue with that approach
this time but still there is always a
probability of amount of disruption
that's the point that I want to make but
I think the larger point is that these
are all in our opinion very positive
changes from a longer term perspective
and we believe should help discipline
Underwriters uh you know players like us
who have capital and and presence across
multiple lines of business at scale I
think it should benefit us but you know
we just wanted to kind of tell you that
there is also a probability of some
amount of uh you know destabilization
given the amount of changes that are
happening that's always a possibility
sure and there's there's a follow-up on
that there is a also talk of
deregulating the commission rate across
online for business while expensive
management will be capped at a
particular level so do you see as a
multi-line insurance company we will
have advantage in the retail health
insurance segment because of that that
regulation so I think the advantage for
us is if you look at the proposed uh
expensive management limit that is being
talked about we are within that number
as a company so we have we are
comfortably placed some of the companies
which have been aggressively going uh
spending a lot of money uh they may have
to calibrate to that extent yes there
could be an advantage
thank you
we'll take the next question from the
line of maduka Lada from newama wealth
management please go ahead
oh hi good evening
um most of my questions have been
answered just a couple of them uh one on
the motor TP segment
um we're seeing a lot of improvement in
the loss ratio
so I'm not sure whether you've clarified
this earlier or not
uh but has there been some improvement
taken from uh you know the the six
months uh uh restriction on the period
of reporting uh any accident uh so so
has uh what have been the developments
on that and uh you know if you could
give us some guidance in terms of how
the courts are ruling and whether there
can be any uh benefit flowing through uh
more and better we have accounted for
any sort of reserved releases because of
that and second uh on the on on the
group others business which is uh
excluding the employer employee uh uh
business uh what is the source of that I
believe you're not doing that business
more with ICC bank so what are the other
what are our other partners
uh you know broadly if you can help us
with you know Banks and BSC some sort of
classification and and against what
products are these attachments
uh on the first one uh
the the first answer is no we have not
taken benefits of the shortening of the
tail uh as yet uh what we've seen happen
is there's been a recent Madras high
court judgment which is uh reaffirming
this point that you have to sub you know
file claims within six months so now we
have case law supporting the change in
the regulation or law of the land which
is a positive what we are see beginning
to see is some signs for for first six
seven months we didn't see me see a big
change in terms of frequency or you know
acceleration of claims but as we speak
early signs of uh some exploration
happening in some states
uh we will have to study this for some
more time to tell you that it's
happening at the national level but
early signs are positive uh and we will
have to uh if that happens then it could
be a positive for uh for the sector but
as of now we've not taken any benefit of
that in our numbers because it's too
early to take a benefit uh in terms of
your second question uh you know this is
this was always our stress working with
multiple vacation companies uh NBA
series hsc's uh we work with uh you know
digital uh you know lending companies we
work with a whole host of uh you know
entities which uh you know provide
retail credit with whom we uh sell some
of these uh group other category of
Health Products uh which is what has
come back which is the point that we
were making that uh last couple of years
there was no that and we had a
relatively higher share of that business
so to that extent it was negative for us
but that has now come back this year and
that's where this is going from ICC Bank
this is on that account what they
previous last year they stopped selling
they haven't restarted that however what
they've done is uh they have started
selling uh Indemnity products retail
Indian reality products both through the
branches as also as attachments for
their uh you know mortgage customers so
that's why the number from the bank side
is also positive
if you look at the percentages we gave
that in the opening remarks
distribution which includes multiple
other Banks so most of the large private
sector Banks we are their Partners most
of the large NPS and hccs we have their
partners and that segment that is
non-iscible and distribution grew at
44.2 percent
thank you
we'll take the next question from the
line of the refrigerator from my Apple
institutional equities please go ahead
thank you
you home yeah thanks for the opportunity
can you hear me clearly
yes is she
yeah so I just you know wanted some uh
you know color on you know how do we
look at the expense ratio trajectory
right so there are two parts to it over
the past 15 months is the acquisition of
bharti AXA there was one uh you know
trajectory which suggested that you know
the gap between the expense ratios uh
between parties and us should converge
over you know two two and a half year
period and that is something that will
drive the overall combined ratio down on
the other hand uh you know we had
intended to basically invest in retail
and Retail health and digital in order
to you know gain some of those shares uh
you know market share there now if I
look at uh you know both these aspects
you know it would be great to just
understand one you know on the bharti
extra rationalization has the progress
being slower than expected and to uh uh
you know we have seen like even on a
nine month basis significant growth
but it doesn't seem to reflect that it
is going into retail Health looking at
the combined ratio of retailers it seems
to be going into motor so just wanted to
understand you know in the second part
you know how the expenses are getting
allocated too and as a result uh what
should be the trajectory going for
uh I think uh uh your second part of the
question with respect to the progress of
the bharti axi integration in line with
what we have been communicating I think
that is pretty much uh we have kind of
realized whatever Villages that we spoke
about I think the only last energy which
we had said is something that we will
realize in this financial year is the
technology Synergy consequent to once we
get the
applications integrated or merged we
should start realizing the benefit of
the Synergy play out from quarter four
of the current year onwards I'm happy to
note that even that particular aspect in
respect of integration between the two
companies have kind of been done and
hence that extent you may start to see
uh the Synergy on the technology cost
play out from Q4 onwards uh to your
first part on with respect to what could
be the trajectory that the expense
ratios could take yes you are right I
think there are multiple aspects that
goes into insofar as determination of
the laundry expense ratio trajectory is
concerned one is the function of what
kind of Revenue growth opportunity that
one sees which is what I had explained
certain lines of businesses while there
are costs that we kind of continue to
incur however the revenue is something
that we have not been able to completely
realize it through its fullest potential
a segment in reference is motor for
example clearly we have not been able to
kind of realize the complete potential
of what we would like to see that
segment operate at now as and when let's
say the growth comes back that itself
will be a function of let's say some
form of efficiencies or maybe some form
of uh Improvement that you will get to
see in so far as the expense ratio the
trajectory is concerned the second is
obviously I as I mentioned the
investments in retail Health to your
other point was not just a one-off
investment it's a continuing one uh we
continue to hire let's say the number of
retail health agency managers who must
we have explained will obviously go and
add more number of agency distribution
so those costs again comes and it says
today in our p l because these are
actual number of employees who are
getting onboarded in so far as retail
health and distribution is concerned so
which is why you will you will continue
until the time let's say the benefits in
the form of incremental Revenue play out
which is what which is in the past also
which we have explained it roughly takes
about 12 to 18 months for the cycle to
completely get uh efficient is when you
will start seeing let's say incremental
revenues being contributed but in so far
as early signs are concerned I think the
investment seems to be kind of laying
out in line with our expectations and
ends to that extent I think we are quite
happy with the way how things are
playing out uh but finally in terms of
what number the expense ratio trajectory
could take I think rather we would look
at it more from a combined ratio
perspective which is a combination of
both expense and loss ratios because
different segmented different outcomes
into in terms of the Way businesses will
get sourced they are clearly what we had
indicated was over a two year period we
would want to see a declining slope on
the combined ratio front and we are
pretty much staying on course with
respect to that particular thought
process of ours who I mean already be in
line with what we have spoken about for
f523 we had said the combined will stay
range Bound in that 104 levels and in fi
24 you will start seeing a declining
slope we are pretty much on course in
order to kind of uh getting that
reflected and hence that's the
trajectory that one would see in so far
as the combined ratios is concerned
thank you
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
a last question I now have the
conference over to Mr bhargav bhaskupta
for closing comments
uh one question yeah I think there was
that one question which hitesh had asked
in the in in the context of how many
agents did we had uh consequent to the
Thousand health agency managers that
number is at about 10 000. agents is
what we have been able to add by these
agency managers that we've had
so again so thank you everyone for uh
for joining the call
it's pretty late for all of you I look
forward to our interaction during the
quarter thank you thank you so much
thank you
ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
icicnumber General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines